University of Connecticut, School of Business Administration Records 1998.0091
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, School of Business Administration Records
undated, 1940-1998
1998.0091
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
7.55 Linear feet
The University of Connecticut's School of Business was established in 1941 as the School of Business Administration. The collection contains faculty minutes, accreditation documentation, and annual activity reports from the school's founding in 1941 until 1998.
University of Connecticut. School of Business Administration.
University of Connecticut. School of Business.
History
Founded in 1941, the University of Connecticut; School of Business Administration (now the School of Business) has evolved into one of the most comprehensive business schools in the nation. In 1947 the school instituted its first academic departments, and included accounting, finance, industrial administration, insurance, law & secretarial studies, and marketing. Beginning in 1964 the school offered a full-time MBA program, extending the the school's original MBA program which had been offered only to U.S. Air Force Officers.
The School of Business currently offers academic programs at the bachelors, masters, doctorate and advanced certificate levels at five Connecticut locations – Storrs, Hartford, Stamford, Torrington and Waterbury, and has established a strong reputation for high quality research and academic programs, spanning a wide array of functional disciplines. The school currently offers degree programs in accounting, finance, management, marketing, and operations and information management.
Deans
Lawrence J. Ackerman, 1941-1963
Robert O. Harvey, 1963-1973
William N. Kinnard, Jr., 1973 (Acting)
Ronald J. Patten, 1974-1989
David S. Kidwell, 1989-1991
John F. Veiga, 1991
Thomas Gutteridge, 1992-2003
William Curt Hunter, 2003-2006
Mo Hussein, 2007
Christopher Earley, 2008-
Scope and Content
The collection contains the faculty minutes, accreditation documents, and annual activity reports for the School of Business at the University of Connecticut from 1940 until 1998. The collection includes materials collected by the school during its accreditation process, and the administrative records to go along with that process. Other materials in the collection include self-study reports, surveys, report of PhD, Baccalaureate and Master programs, work order forms, telephone service request forms, furniture moves, transfer or retirement of equipment and supplies forms, and other various administrative records. The collection includes records from the time of the School's founding in 1941 and up to 1998.
Related materials can be found in the School's Annual reports and Biographical (Faculty) Directories both of which are located in the serials holdings of Archives & Special Collections; additional ephemeral materials can be found in the ASC subject files under "School of Business."
Acquisition Information
The School of Business materials have been transferred to the University Archives in periodic installments beginning in 1979.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
University of Connecticut.; Administrative Records.; Business schools--Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Minutes.; Notebooks.; Photocopies.; Publications.; Storrs (Conn.)
- Series I: Minutes, 1940-1990; Series I:
  - 1940-1960 (Box 1)
  - 1961-1976 (Box 2)
  - 1977-1983 (Box 5)
  - 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - 1986-1990 (Box 7)
- Series II: Accreditation documentation, 1969-1998; Series II:
  - Administrative records, 1969-1973 (Box 2001-0058_1)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Subjects include: Accreditation self-study report, survey, faculty and other data.]
  - Administrative records, 1982-1983 (Box 2001-0058_2)
    [Subjects include: Accreditation, survey, report of PhD, Baccalaureate and Master program.]
  - Administrative records, 1996-1998 (Box 2001-0058_3)
- Series III: Small Business Management Research Reports, 1959-1979; Series III:
  - 1959-1961 (Box 3)
  - 1961-1979 (Box 4)
- Series IV: Annual Activity Reports and Inventory, 1989-1998; Series IV:
  - Administrative Records, Clippings, Correspondence, Financial Records, 1989-1998; 1.3 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2001-0094_1)
    [Subjects Include: Annual Activity Reports, Faculty Evaluations: Operation and Information Management, Finance, Marketing, Management and Accounting Departments, Department Head Evaluations, Inventory of University Equipment, Work Order Forms, Telephone Service Request Forms.]
  - Administrative Records, Correspondence, 1990-1997; 0.5 Linear feet Folders with labeled tabs. (Box 2001-0094_2)
    [Subjects Include: Furniture Moves, Transfer or Retirement of Equipment and Supplies Forms.]